Guide to the Eleanor Gibson Papers, 1906-1999, 1935-1999 (bulk)
Gibson, Eleanor Papers, 1906-1999, 1935-1999 (bulk)
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Eleanor Gibson papers, 1906-1999, 1935-1999
14-23-2658
Eleanor Gibson
21 cubic ft.
Correspondence, articles, notes, slides, photographs, videotapes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library.
Material relating to Eleanor J. Gibson's education, research, and career as a Professor of Psychology.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Psychology and holder of the Susan Linn Sage Chair, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes Eleanor Gibson's Masters Thesis from Smith; PhD Thesis from Yale; and other material from her graduate studies. Items relating to her teaching career include lecture notes, demonstration materials, experiment designs, examinations and students' papers. Also included are grant proposals and data from experiments conducted at Cornell's Graduate Psychological Laboratories in various aspects of perception and learning such as childhood reading disorders, scanning, word perception, and information processing; material for Psychology of Reading; and An Odyssey in Learning and Perception; vitae and biographical sketches; 1992 National Medal of Science Award memorabilia; articles by Eleanor J. Gibson, James J. Gibson, and other psychology scholars separated by author and subject; notes and slides for lectures, talks, and colloquiums; folders of correspondence; tape recording of E.G. Boring's 1967 speech on the founding of the Society of Experimental Psychologists delivered at the centennial of the birth of Edward B. Titchener; and assorted floppy disks.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Gibson, Eleanor Jack.; Boring, E.G.; Cornell University. Dept. of Psychology.; Cornell University. Graduate Psychological Laboratories.; Society of Experimental Psychologists.
Subjects:
Psychology--Study and teaching.; Environmental psychology.; Learning, Psychology of.; Reading, Psychology of.; Perceptual learning.; Perception.; Children--Research.; Women college students.
Occupations:
Women psychologists.; Psychologists.; Women college teachers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
Gibson, James J. papers,1922-1980.
Interviews by Kathryn M. Moore, 1975-1976.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Eleanor Gibson Material, 1933-1999
Material from Eleanor Gibson's undergraduate and graduate studies including her masters and doctoral theses, vitae and biographical sketches, correspondence, material relating to her 1992 National Medal of Science Award, and articles written by Eleanor Gibson.
Series II. Subject Files, 1906-1998
Notes and articles arranged by subject.
Series III. Psychology Scholar Files, 1941-1997
Notes and articles by colleagues and other psychology scholars
Series IV. Talks, Lectures, and Classes, 1931-1998
Notes, slides, and articles for classes, lectures, and talks.
Series V. Experiments and Grants, 1943-1980
Grant proposals, data from experiments.
Series VI. Book Publication Files 1917-1978
Material for book
Series VII. Miscellaneous
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Eleanor Gibson Material
  - Memoir:family biographical materials, 1978-2001 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Master's Thesis:Efficiency of Retention as Dependent Upon the Similarity of the Interpolated Task, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - E.J.G.'s Notebook from Yale (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Comparative Psychobiology notes from Yale (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Animal Psychology notes from Yale (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Syllabus from Yale class, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Articles by E.J.G., 1937-1979 (Box 12, Folder 1--22)
  - Doctoral Thesis:A Systematic Application of the Concepts of Generalization And Differentiation to Verbal Learning, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Studies in Generalization and Differentiation: 5 articles by E.J.G., 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Six articles by E.J.G.: Studies in Generalization and Differentiation, 1939-1959 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence: 1939 - 1943, 1963 -1968 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Elkind, David - correspondence regarding E.J.G.'s Learning to Read article in Science, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1972 - 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1974-1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Articles by E.J.G. and biographical sketch from A History of Psychology in Autobiography, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: 1980 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: January - June 1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: July - December 1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Articles by E.J.G., 1981-1992 (Box 12, Folder 24-34)
  - Correspondence: January - April 1982 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: May - December 1982 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: 1983 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: 1984 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Dartmouth 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: 1985 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: 1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: 1987 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: 1988 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - International Society of Ecological Psychology, 1988-1993 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: 1989 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: 1990 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: 1991 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Article: Eleanor J. Gibson: Learning to Perceive and Perceiving to Learn, by Herbert L. Pick Jr., 1992 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence: 1992 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - National Medal of Science Award material, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Articles by E.J.G., 1993 (Box 12, Folder 36-38)
  - Correspondence: 1993 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: 1994 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Paper on George Elliot for book group, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence: 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Articles by E.J.G., 1996-1997 (Box 12, Folder 40-41)
  - Articles by E.J.G.,undated, ca. 1990-1997 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: 1997-1999 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Vitae and biographical sketches (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Series II. Subject Files
  - A Linguistic Analysis of First Grade Reading Errors (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Acquired Distinctiveness (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Affordances, 1938-1976 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Affordances, 1977-1986 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Affordances 1981-1988 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Affordances, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Affordances, 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Affordances, 1991 - 1993 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Animal studies: Bats: sonar signal processing 1976 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Animal studies: birds: migration, sensory perception studies 1958-1975 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Animal studies: hummingbirds: adaptation, decision making 1981-1993 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Animal studies: birds: prenatal behavior 1970 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Animal studies: California sea lion: attention shift and errorless reversal learning 1967 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Animal studies: cats, rats: sensory discrimination, brain function 1934-1970 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Animal studies: elephant seal dialects 1969 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Animal studies: environment and ecology 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Animal studies: hearing in animals 1973 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Animal studies: insects: sensory perception, motor patterns 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Animal studies: language in non-human (primates mostly) 1969-1981 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Animal studies: monkeys: sensory perception, discrimination, language, developmental behavior, intelligence 1940-1977 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Animal studies: planaria: conditioned discrimination 1964 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Animal studies: quails and rats: sensory cues and aversions, discrimination learning, perceptual organization 1950-1971 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Animal studies: snakes: chemical-cue preferences of newborn 1971 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Animal studies: discrimination, stroboscopic movement 1953-1965 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Aphasia and Localization articles, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Aphasia and Localization articles, 1962-1968 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - APU Reprints: linguistic psychology articles, 1963-1966 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Articles on Information, Events, and Affordances, 1977-1986 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Articles on Perceptual Theory, 1955-1986 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Articulation articles, 1962-1966 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Auditory perception and reading 1962-1965 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Bibliography of Baby Biographies (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bilingualism, 1962-1968 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Categorical Perception, 1949-1977 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Categorical Perception, 1979-1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Causality, Predictability, and Intention 1956-1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Causality, Predictability, and Intention 1979-1990 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Classic Reprints:articles collected by E.J.G., 1935-1959 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Cloze Procedure - Readability, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Cognition, 1969-1982 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Cognition, 1983- 1987 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Cognitive processes 1960 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Color Vision in infants, 1974-1977 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Communication in infants 1977-1996 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Comparative Psychology: old reprints, 1951-1953 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Concept Formation, 1957-1964 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Concepts and memory 1985 1993 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Confusion Matrices in Speech Communication, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Confusion Matrices, 1957-1971 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Connectionism, 1988-1997 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Control 1967-1994 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Control and intentionality 1979-1989 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Core knowledge 1992-1998 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Cultural Differences in Perception, 1973-1976 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Deaf Reading, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Development 1994-1998 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Developmental Psychology, 1941-1986 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Differentiation and Predifferentiation, 1942-1962 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Dyslexia: notes, articles, papers, 1931, 1960-1965 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Dyslexia: notes, articles, papers, 1966-1970 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Dyslexia: notes, articles, papers, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Dyslexia: notes, articles, papers, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Early Learning 1971-1994 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Ecological self 1973-1990 (Box 16, Folder 27-28)
  - Environmental Psychology, 1975-1988 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Event Perception, 1957-1977 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Event Perception, 1978-1981 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Event Perception, 1982-1984 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Event Perception, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Event Perception, 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Event Perception, 1988-1991 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Exploration and Action, 1950-1977 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Exploration and Action, 1978 -1984 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Exploration and Action, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Extrinsic Awards and Motivation, 1959-1975 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Faces 1970-1977 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Faces 1978-1985 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Faces 1986-1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Fairy tales 1944-1992 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Flexibility 1978-1996 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Flow Patterns 1971-1984 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Flow Patterns 1985-1990 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Form and Shape, Perception and Discrimination, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Form and Shape, Perception and Discrimination, 1960-1962 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Functionalism (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Gestalt Principles 1937-1981 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Grammatical Categories in Learning, 1961-1965 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - History of Child Psychology, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Humans: early development 1970 1987 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Infant Hearing 1963-1984 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Information Processing and Sequential Relationship, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Information Processing, 1958-1992 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Intermodal 1977-1998 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Intermodal Perception, 1927-1977 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Intermodal Perception, 1978-1982 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Intermodal Perception, 1983-1989 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Language Development, 1959-1977 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Language Development, 1978-1982 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Language Development, 1983-1984 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Language Development, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Language Development, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Language Development, 1989-1991 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Language Development, 1993-1996 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Learning: notes 1987-1995 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Learning theory 1966-1989 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Learning theory: its foundations in early development 1990-1995 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Learning to read 1965 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Locomotion - optical 1978-1996 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Locomotor development 1958-2001 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Mirror Research, 1906-1978 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Nature of perceptual change 1976-1994 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Burr's Comparative Neurology (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Objects, 1965-1986 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Objects, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Objects, 1967-1997 (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
  - Old Form Perception Reprints, 1920-1949 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Old Form Perception Reprints, 1951-1956 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Old Form Perception Reprints, 1958-1961 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Optics of Infancy, 1957-1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Perception of Order and Regularity, 1963-1965 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Perception, Perceptual Learning, 1920-1956 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Perception, Perceptual Learning, 1957-1963 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Perception, Perceptual Learning, 1964-1972 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Perception, Perceptual Learning, 1975-1989 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Perceptual Development and Reading Research, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Perceptual judgement 1952 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Perceptual learning 1955-2001 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Phylogenesis of Vision, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Phylogeny of Perception 1958-1999 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Pictoral Perception, 1906-1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Pictoral Perception, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Pictoral Perception, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Pictoral Perception, 1982-1988 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Preadapted Coordination of systems, 1970-1979 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Preadapted Coordination of systems, 1980-1986 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Primate Perception and Learning reprints, 1938-1953 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Proximity Analysis for Information Processing, 1962, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Reading articles, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Reading in Children with Sensory and Motor Defects: papers and bibliography, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Reading Research Quarterly, Winter 1965, Winter 1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Reading Skills, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Receptive fields 1940-1977 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Reprints on Attention, 1918-1928 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Role of Inflection in Word Perception, paper and notes, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Scanning and Detection articles, 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Self: as agent 1976-1995 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Self: differentiation from world 1974-1989 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Self: specification as a place 1974-1986 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Sensory perception: binocular depth perception 1974 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Sensory perception and thinking 1939-1972 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Space 1946-1995 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Spatial Perception, 1956-1981 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Spatial Perception, 1982-1986 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Spatial Perception, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Spatial Perception, 1989-1995 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Spelling patterns, 1960-1968 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Spelling patterns, 1960-1968 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Stroop Effect in Chinese Children (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Supporting surfaces 1978-1992 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - The Cognitive Basis for Linguistic Structures, T.G. Bever, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Tools and Tool Use, 1932-1997 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Transfer and flexibility in skill development 1992-1995 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Transformational Theory of Grammar and Language, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Unit Formation, 1959-1964 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Visual perception 1956-1972 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Visual perception and distance 1952-1961 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Visual perception and reading 1962-1977 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Visual System/Visual Cliff, 1949-1982 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Word Association Reprints, 1962-1965 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Word Classification, 1961-1964 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Word Perception Articles, 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Word Perception: Haskins Laboratories, Alvin M. Liberman articles, 1951-1959 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Word Perception: Haskins Laboratories, Alvin M. Liberman articles, 1960-1965 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Writing, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Nature of perceptual change 1976-1994 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Floppy disks: articles and chapters (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Card file: articles (Box 17, Folder 22)
- Series III. Psychology Scholar Files
  - Adolf, Karen (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Adolf, Karen (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Bahrick, Lorraine E. 1998-2001 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Baillargeon, Renee, ca. 1987 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Best, Catherine Therese, 1981-1994 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Bingham, Geoffrey P., 1989-1993 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Bower, T.G.R., 1964-1992 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Brill, Blandine, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Church, Joseph, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Clifton, Rachel K., 1988-1997 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Clifton, Rachel K., 2000-2002 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Ellis, Henry C., 1962-1967 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Ellis, Henry C., 1968 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Eppler,Marion, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Evans, Selby, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Fantz, Robert E., 1956-1967 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Fraiberg, Selma, ca. 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Garcia, John, 1966-1987 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Gibson,James J., 1944-1998 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Granrud, Carl E. 1988 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Gustafson, Gwen E. 1979-1988 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Hagen, Margaret, 1978-1990 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Hull, Clark L. 1929-1952 (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
  - Hull [Clark L.] and Tolman [Edward C.]: notes, reprints 1929-1942 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Keil, Frank, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Kellman, Philip J. 1987-1992 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Landau, Barbara, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Lee, David, 1976-1992 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Lipsitt, Lewis P., 1979-1982 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Mandler, Jean, 1977-1993 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Menzel, Emil 1964-1983 (Box 18, Folder 7-8)
  - Miller, David B. 1988 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Neisser, Ulric, 1964-1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Newell, Karl, 1986, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Reed, Edward S., 1994-1995 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Rieser, John, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Rochat, Philippe, 1988-1994 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Rochat, Philippe, 1995-1997 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Rosch, Eleanor, 1971-1976 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Rovee-Collier, Carolyn, 1978-1986 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Schmuckler, Mark A., 1990 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Slater, Alan, 1985-1990 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Smitsman, Ad W., 1985-1988 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Spelke, Elizabeth, 1976-1992 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Spelke, Elizabeth, 1976-1992 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Spelke, Elizabeth, 1998-2002 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Tenney, Yvette: 1973 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Thelen, Esther, 1984-1986 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Tolman, Edward C. 1935-1951 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Trevarthen, Colwyn, 1978-1989 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Turvey, M.T., 1986-1991 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Von Hofsten, Claes, 1982-1985 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Von Hofsten, Claes, 1988-1996 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Vurpillot, Eliane, 1956-1959 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Vurpillot, Eliane, 1960-1964 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Walker-Andrews, Arlene, 1988-1994 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Weigl, Egon:On the Psychology of So-called Processes of Abstraction, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Series IV. Talks, Lectures, and Classes
  - Comparative Psychology Course: Mr. Pierce's collection of articles, 1907-1914 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Comparative Psychology Course, ca. 1931-1939 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Comparative Psychology Course: Bibliographies, Notes, Articles, 1931-1939 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Comparative Psychology Course: Illustrative Material, ca. 1931-1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Comparative Psychology Course: 34a Lectures on genetic psychology, ca. 1931-1939 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Comparative Psychology Course: 34a Reading lists, exams, 1931-1936 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Child Development Seminar, ca. 1933-1939 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Comparative Psychology Course: 34a Course Lectures, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Preadapted coordinations: internodal equivalence and coordination 1937-1978 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Preadapted coordinations: intermodal relations 1937-1984 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Comparative Psychology Course: 34a Course, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Comparative Psychology Course: Maze Experiment, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Comparative Psychology Course: Notes on Animal Genetic Psychology for 34a, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Comparative Psychology Course: Questionnaires on Animal Psychology from 34a, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Learning Review for Seniors, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Comparative Psychology Course: 34b Course, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Comparative Psychology Course: 34b Course 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Comparative Psychology Course: 34b Course, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Comparative Psychology Course: 34b Course Outlines, 1941-1942, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Psychology 11: Lectures, Smith College, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Psychology 11: Old Experiments and Special Lectures, Smith College, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Psychology 12: Course outlines, Smith College, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Psychology 12: Course outlines and exams, Smith College, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Psychology 12: Course notes, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Psychology 12: First Semester, Smith College, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Psychology 12: Outlines, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Psychology 12: First and Second Year Quizzes, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Psychology 12: Midyear exams, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Psychology 12: Spring Quiz, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Psychology 12: Final Examination, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Psychology 12: Demonstration Materials, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Psychology 12: Sample Final Examination from Dartmouth, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Psychology 12: Sample Final Examination, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Comparative Psychology Course Notes, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Psychology 208:Learning, Exams, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Psychology 208:Learning, Lecture outlines, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Psychology 208:Learning, Material, 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Photograph of Black Abstraction by Georgia O'Keefe, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Differentiation 1955-2001 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Motivation: visual stimuli (see also affordances) 1956 1979 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Events: lecture notes, reprints 1957-1979 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - What Psychology is about 1957-2001 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Visual Cliff material for speech at Barnard, ca. 1961 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Active Touch Photographs, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Learning Project Conference Papers, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Learning Project Conference Papers, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Learning Project Conference Papers, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Linguistics Seminar, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Perceptual and Linguistic Aspects of Reading Skill, conference papers, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Perceptual and Linguistic Aspects of Reading Skill, conference papers, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Berkeley Seminar on Cognitive Studies and Curriculum Development, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)